我刚看过了
Okay,I checked.
我们有伯爵茶,英式早餐茶,肉桂茶
We have Earl Grey,English Breakfast,Cinnamon Stick...
菊花茶,薄荷茶,黑莓茶
...Chamomile,Mint Medley,Blackberry and
还有…柠檬派
Wait,there's one more. Lemon Soother!
你不是那个要喝茶的人对吧?
You're not the guy that asked for tea,are you?
六人行 第1季 第19集 猴子跑了
The One Where The Monkey Gets Away
瑞秋,你有信
Mail call! Rachel Greene,bunk seven.
谢谢
Thank you.
酷,免费试喝的咖啡
Oh,cool! A free sample of coffee.
太好了,因为在哪儿还有免费的咖啡?
Oh,good. Because where else would we get any?
哦,是啊
Oh,right.
-太好了 -那是什么?
-Oh,great. -What is it?
乡村俱乐部的每日公报
Country club newsletter.
我妈寄来通知有人要订婚了
My mother sends me the engagement notices for inspiration.
噢,我的天!是贝瑞和明蒂
Oh,my God! It's Barry and Mindy!
贝瑞,你几乎…
Barry,who you almost
明蒂,你的伴娘
And Mindy,your maid of
我看看,那是明蒂?
Let me see. That's Mindy?
真漂亮!
She is pretty!
她真幸运…
Lucky...
有你这样的朋友
...to have had a friend like you.
现在是静默时间
Now it's quiet time.
马修,拿饭给我,快…
Marcel,bring me the rice. Come on.
好小子.把饭给我
Good boy. Give me the rice.
真乖,谢谢
Thank you. Good boy.
他终于能分辨“拿来”和“尿在”的差别了
He's mastered the difference between "bring me the" and "pee in the."
瑞秋怎么啦?
"Bring me the" and Rach?
抱歉
Oh,I'm sorry.
我真是太笨了
This is so stupid!
是我不要贝瑞的,对吧?
I mean,I gave Barry up,right?
我应该为他们高兴
I should be happy for them.
我…真为他们高兴
I am. I'm happy for them.
-真的? -不
-Really? -No.
如果我和别人在一起就不同了
I guess it would be different if I were with somebody.
谁,什么…
Whoa,what....
你不是说要忘了那段感情,不再和男人在一起
What happened to "Forget relationships! I'm done with men!"
禁止所有阴茎吗?
The whole penis embargo?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想这不是没有男人的问题,而是合适男人的问题
It's not about no guys. It's about the right guy.
和贝瑞在一起安全自在 但是没有激情
With Barry it was safe and easy,but there was no heat.
和保罗在一起就充满激情
With Paolo,all there was,was heat.
-如野兽般原始的性爱 -好了,我懂
-lt was this raw,animal,sexual -Right. I got it.
我看过你们两个在一起的样子
I was there.
你认为我能两者同时拥有吗?
Do you think you can have both?
找到一个能当知己 又能让我感受到激情的人?
Someone who's your best friend but also can make your toes curl.
是呀
Yes.
我也这么认为.我真的这么认为
Yes,I do. I really do.
其实说来好笑
In fact,it's funny.
时常你认为
Often,someone you wouldn't think could...
无法让你感受到激情的人
...curl your toes...
却是…
... might just be the one who...
被打断了
...gets interrupted.
电影如何?
How was the movie?
-很不错 -很不错
-Wonderful! -So good!
-逊毙了 -根本是小妞们看的嘛
-Suck fest. -Total chick flick.
真遗撼这不是枪林弹雨
I'm sorry it wasn't one of those movies with guns and bombs...
公车速度奇快的那种电影
...and buses going really fast!
暴力并不能吸引我
I don't need violence in a movie...
只要有裸体镜头我就满足了
...as long as there's a little nudity.
-那电影也有裸体镜头 -我是指女生的裸体镜头
-There was nudity. -I meant female nudity.
我不爱看卢格兰特的激情戏
I don't need to see Lou Grant frolicking.
是休格兰特（《诺丁山》主演）!
Hugh! Hugh Grant!
我得走了
All right,I've got to go.
走吧,马修,快
Come on,Marcel.
我们去洗澡,对不对?对
We're gonna go take a bath. Yes,we are,aren't we?
他们只是朋友吗?
They're still just friends,right?
明天见
And I will see you tomorrow.
对,你明天要跟瑞秋阿姨待在一起
You're gonna spend tomorrow at Aunt Rachel's.
等等,莫妮卡阿姨对这件事能有发言权吗?
Does Aunt Monica get a say in this?
莫妮卡阿姨请说吧
Please,Aunt Monica,please?
别紧张了,你不会留在这儿的的
Unclench. You're not even gonna be here.
-我无法相信我们竟在讨论此事 -我同意,我也无法相信
-I can't believe we're discussing this. -I agree. I'm,like,in disbelief.
如果你和瑞秋会产生爱情的话 还会一直拖到现在吗?
If it was gonna happen,wouldn't it have happened already?
她说她在寻找像我这样的人
She said she wants a relationship with someone exactly like me.
她真的这样说?
She said that?
“像我这样”是我自己加的
I added the exactly like me" part.
她说她在寻找某人,而此人今晚就会出现
But she's looking for someone. And someone will be there tonight.
今天晚上?
"Tonight" tonight?
这样最好不过了,因为只有我们两个
It's perfect. It'll just be the two of us.
她整天都在照顾我的猴子
She spent all day taking care of my monkey.
我早已忘记哪个女人照顾过我的“猴子”
I can't remember the last time a girl took care of my monkey.
总之下班后我要去买瓶酒…
Anyway,I figured after work,I'd pick up some wine...
去向她“示爱”
...go over there and try to woo her.
知道你该怎么做吗?
Know what you should do?
带她回到用“示爱”表达的1890年去
Take her back to the 1 890s when that phrase was last used.
如果你继续这样,我发誓这星期内 你就可以和这个浑蛋结束
If you keep this up,you'll be finished by the weekend.
围羽毛围巾的是弗兰西斯博土
The one in the feathered boa is Dr. Francis.
她曾是个男人
Now,she used to be a man.
蕾文出现了
Look,there's Raven.
我们讨厌她,真高兴她就快死了
We hate her. We're glad she's dying.
什么?马修!
And then What? Marcel!
想玩莫妮卡的鞋吗?你不能玩…
Are you playing with Monica's shoes? You're not supposed to
马修,你在鞋里大便?
Marcel,did you poo in the shoe?
天啊,坏猴子
Oh,Marcel! Bad monkey!
哦,天哪!
Oh,God!
抱歉,贝瑞
Sorry,Barry.
一份小小的订婚礼物
A little engagement gift.
我相信你没注册这个
I'm sure you didn't register for that.
谁死了?谁死了?
Who died? Who died?
翻过去!好不好,翻过去!
Roll him over! Come on,roll him over!
好吧,我们知道不是崔斯勒,因为…马修?…
Well,we know it wasn't Dexter,right,Marcel? Because
马修?
Marcel?
-你怎会把他弄丢了呢? -天晓得
-How could you lose him? -I don't know!
我正在看电视,他在莫妮卡的鞋内大便
We were watching TV,he pooped in Monica's shoe....
他在我的鞋里大便?哪一双?
Wait. He pooped in my shoe? Which one?
我不知道,左脚
I don't know. The left one!
是哪一双?
Which ones?
那双你觉得搭配什么都好看的厚底的门诺教派（指朴素））什么的
Those little clunky Amish things you think go with everything.
为何一片愁云惨雾?
Why is the air in here so negative?
瑞秋把马修弄丢了
Rachel lost Marcel.
不会吧,怎么丢的?
Oh,no! How?
-他在我鞋里大便 -哪只?
-He pooped in my shoe. -Which one?
我常穿的那只可爱黑鞋
The cute black ones I always wear.
是哪一只?
No,which one?
左脚还是右脚?
The right or left?
因为左脚表示幸运
Because the left one is lucky.
大家快想办法!我该怎么办?
Come on! What am I gonna do?
有了,如果你是只猴子,迷失在大城市时
All right. You're a monkey. You're loose in the city.
你会去哪儿?
Where do you go?
这是他第一次出门,所以大概和一般游客一样
It's his first time out,so he'll do touristy things.
我去上演《猫》的地方找.你去俄罗斯茶室（世贸中心的著名餐厅）
I'll go to Cats. You go to the Russian Tea Room.
别再闹了!
Oh,my God! Come on,you guys!
他马上就会回家,他不会饶过我的
He'll be home any minute. He's gonna kill me!
找整栋楼，你们找一楼,我们找其他的
Search the building. Take the first floor. We'll take the rest.
我该怎么办?
What am I gonna do?
你留在家里等电话
You stay here and wait by the phone.
在我鞋内喷“来苏儿”消毒水,顺便等罗斯回来杀你
Spray Lysol in my shoe and wait for Ross to kill you.
有人要交换吗?
Does anybody want to trade?
干嘛?
What do you want?
哈克先生,我们朋友遗失了一只猴子 你有看见吗?
Mr. Heckles,have you seen a monkey?
我放了威化饼在这儿,是不是你拿了?
I left a Belgian waffle out here. Did you take it?
-你怎会放威化饼在走廊? -我还不想吃
-Why'd you leave it in the hall? -I wasn't ready for it.
你有看见猴子吗?
Have you seen a monkey?
我见过吉斯・菲尔宾（主持人）
I saw Regis Philbin once.
谢谢你,哈克先生
Thank you,Mr. Heckles.
你们欠我威化饼
You owe me a waffle.
他是一只白脸的黑卷尾猴
He's a black capuchin monkey with a white face...
加俄国酱外加腌黄瓜
...with Russian dressing and pickles on the side.
好,谢谢
Thanks.
今天过得如何?
How did it go today?
很好啊!很好啊.真的很不错
Oh,great! It went great. Really great.
那是酒吗?
Is that wine?
是的,想喝吗?
You want some?
我非常乐意来点
Oh,I would love some.
可是我们别在这儿喝
But let's not drink it here.
我感觉有点疯狂,我们去纽瓦克市好吗?
I'm feeling crazy. You wanna go to Newark?
前往这东北犯罪首府之前…
Okay,but before we head off to the murder capital of the Northeast...
…我有些话想说
... I kind of wanted to run something by you.
我们曾谈过…
You know how we were talking before...
…感情的问题
...about relationships,and stuff.
-罗斯,我不能这么做! -你回绝得很快而且很伤人
-Oh,God,Ross,I cannot do this! -Okay,quick and painful.
哦,上帝啊!
Oh,God!
好吧,好吧
Okay,all right. All right,okay.
罗斯,别恨我
Please don't hate me.
到底是什么?
What?
马修他…
You know Marcel?
我好像把他…弄丢了
I kind of lost him.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
我只是麻烦你别让他跑出去
All I asked you to do was keep him in here!
我知道,对不起
I know. I'm sorry.
不,我该负一半的责任
It's partially my fault.
我不该叫你照顾猴子
I shouldn't have had you start with a monkey.
应该叫你照顾铅笔才对
You should have started with a pencil.
罗斯,我已尽最大的努力 我已叫大家分头去找
I'm doing everything I can. Everyone's looking for him and I got
-是谁? -动物控制中心
-Who is it? -Animal Control.
-瞧,我甚至打给动物控制中心 -你打给动物控制中心?
-I've even got Animal Control. -You called Animal Control?
怎么了?你不喜欢他们?
Why? Do you not like them?
马修是非法的外来动物
Marcel is an illegal exotic animal.
我是非法饲养.万一被他们找到他们就会带走他
I'm not allowed to have him. If they find him,they'll take him away.
好吧,可是,你从来就没有告诉大家
Well,now,see,you never ever told us that.
没错,因为我没想到你会请他们来家里
Because I never expected you to invite them to the apartment!
谢谢你来
Thanks for coming.
有人遗失猴子?
Somebody called about a monkey?
对,这完全是个误会
You know,that was a complete misunderstanding.
我以为我们有养猴子,但是我们没有
We thought we had a monkey,but we didn't.
-结果是帽子 -猫!
-Turned out it was a hat. -Cat!
我们查过了,没人看到马修
We checked,no one's seen Marcel.
-我叔叔马修 -那猴子是以你叔叔命名?
-My uncle Marcel. -ls that who the monkey's named after?
你知道持有非法外来动物
Possession of an illegal exotic is punishable...
可判刑两年并没收动物?
... by two years in prison and confiscation of the animal.
天啊
Oh,my God!
你要把这可怜的小东西关进监牢?
You'd put that poor little creature in jail?
菲比,你记得如何先对自己小声说吗?
Remember how we talked about saying things quietly to yourself first?
记得,但总不是时候
Yes,but there isn't always time.
我相信我们能以友善的方式处理,请坐
I'm sure there's some friendly way to reconcile this. Have a seat.
首先,我们还没介绍自己,我叫莫妮卡
We haven't met. I'm Monica Geller.
天啊,你是莫妮卡
Oh,my God,you are!
还有,你是瑞秋格林对吗?
And you're Rachel Greene!
露莎珍妮提,林肯高中
Luisa Gianetti! Lincoln High?
我坐在你们后面
I sat behind you guys in homeroom.
露莎!哦,天哪!
Luisa! Oh,my God!
莫妮卡,是露莎
Monica! It's Luisa!
我也去过那里!
I went there too!
是在后面那个?
Luisa! From homeroom!
你们根本不知道我是谁对不?
You have no idea who I am,do you?
-不 -一点也不
-No. -Not at all.
或许你们那四年,都在当我不存在
Well,maybe that's because you spent four years ignoring me.
难道说“早安,露莎”
Would it have been hard to say,"Morning,Luisa"...
或“好漂亮的连身裤”有那么困难吗?
...or "Nice overalls"?
对不起
Oh,I'm so sorry!
我不怪你,你当时很胖,你有自己的烦恼
It's not so much you. You were fat. You had your own problems.
可是你实在是个贱货
But you. What a bitch!
什么?
What?
别计较了
You know what? Be that as it may...
猴子的事情你能帮我们吗? 看在过去的份上?
...could you help us with the monkey thing,for old times'sake?
加油！山猫队（高中运动队的名字，唤起回忆和亲近感）
Go,Bobcats!
我可以,但我拒绝
I could. But I won't.
如果我找到猴子,他就是我的了
If I find that monkey,he's mine.
抱歉
Sorry.
马修?
Marcel?
需要帮忙吗?
Hi,can I help you?
我们有急事,我们在找东西
We're having an emergency,and we were looking for something.
-猴子 -对,你有看见吗?
-A monkey. -Yes,have you seen any?
我没看见猴子
No,I haven't seen a monkey.
你知道如何修理散热器吗?
Can you fix radiators?
当然!你试过将转钮转回去吗?
Sure! Did you try turning the knob back the other way?
-当然! -那我就不知道了
-Of course! -Oh. Then,no.
-试试这个是不是加太多兰姆酒了? -等等
-Taste this. Is there too much rum? -Just a second.
-希望你们能找到猴子 -不,等等
-Hope you find your monkey. -No,wait!
我们对散热器或许不太懂
We may not know about radiators...
我们可是冷暖环境的专家
... but we do have expertise in the heating and cooling milieu.
我们不是正在忙吗?
Aren't we in the middle of something?
对,她们很热而且需要帮助
But these women are very hot,and they need our help.
而且很火辣
And they're very hot!
我们不行
We can't,all right?
抱歉
We're sorry.
你们不知道我们有多抱歉,我们答应人家要找猴子
You don't know how sorry. We promised to find this monkey.
他约这么高,名叫马修
He's this high and answers to the name Marcel.
如果能拥有你们的照片,就算是帮了大忙
So if we could get pictures of you,it'd help us out.
从现在起不准你和其他人讲话
From now on,you don't get to talk to other people.
高压危险
-噢,我的天! -什么?
-Oh,my God! -What?
有东西碰到我的右脚
Something brushed up against my right leg.
没什么,是我的左脚
Oh,it's okay. It was just my left leg.
看,菲比
Look,Phoebe!
马修,过来…
Oh,Marcel! Come here!
站过去,两位小姐
Step aside,ladies.
-你要干什么? -打镇定剂
-What are you gonna do? -Just a tranquilizer.
快跑,马修,快跑!
Run,Marcel,run!
坏了!
Damn!
-你还好吧? -还行.哦
-Are you okay? -I think so.
哦，糟了!
Oh,gosh!
我们把周围的邻居都找遍了,他不见了,就这么消失了
We've been all over the neighborhood! He's just gone!
-罗斯,还不一定 -拜托,天气好冷天又黑
-You don't know that. -It's cold,it's dark.
他根本不认识路!
He doesn't know the Village!
现在我的脚又受伤了,猴子没了脚又受伤
And now I have a broken foot. I have no monkey and a broken foot!
真的感谢你!
Thank you very much!
罗斯,我已向你道歉过无数次
I've said I'm sorry a million times.
你到底要我怎么样?
What do you want me to do?
你也要我的脚受伤?要我也把脚弄伤
You want me to break my foot too? I'll break it right now.
瞧,高兴了吧
Oh,my God! There,are you happy now?
对,你踢完路标后
Yeah,now that you kicked the sign...
我突然不再想念马修了
... I don't miss Marcel anymore!
我真的不是故意的
It's not like I did this on purpose.
当然,这是典型的瑞秋
No,this is just vintage Rachel.
这种事常发生在你身上
Things just sort of happen around you!
你活在瑞秋的世界中 做着瑞秋的事情…
You're off in "Rachel Land," doing your "Rachel Thing"...
完全无视别人的猴子,或是别人的感觉…
...oblivious to people's monkeys or to people's feelings and
罗斯,我不想听!忘了他,好不好?
I don't want to hear it! Forget it,okay?
什么?
What?
嗨,香蕉男!
Hey,banana man!
这下可好
This is so intense!
一边的屁股在睡觉,另一边却毫不知情
One side of my butt is totally asleep and the other side has no idea.
-菲比怎么啦? -麻醉枪
-What's with Phoebe? -Tranquilizer dart.
你有订香蕉吗?
Hi! Did you order some bananas?
-那是干吗的? -还我的猴子
-What about it? -Give me my monkey back!
-我没猴子 -干嘛买一箱香蕉?
-I don't have a monkey. -Then what's with the bananas?
补充钾
Potassium.
马修?他在哪儿?
Okay,where is he?
你在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
什么?
What?
-你对他干了什么? -这是我的猴子,他叫佩蒂
-What have you done to him? -That's my monkey. That's Patty.
你疯了不成?过来,马修…
Are you insane? Come here,Marcel.
过来,佩蒂
Come here,Patty.
过来,马修…
Come here,Marcel.
过来,佩蒂
Come here,Patty.
猴子过来…
Here,monkey.
过来,猴子!
Here,monkey!
逮到你了
Gotcha!
-把我的猴子还给我 -那是我的猴子
-Give me my monkey back! -It's mine.
你们到法官面前去争吧
Take this up with the judge.
那不是我的猴子 只有衣服是我的,随时可以送回来
That's not my monkey. The dress is mine. Send it back whenever.
好吧,我要我的猴子!
All right,I want my monkey!
-露莎,拜托 -抱歉了,舞会皇后
-Oh,come on,Luisa. -Sorry,prom queen.
你高中时干嘛那么贱,为何不当个胖妹?
You had to be a bitch in school,instead of fat.
在学校我是舞会皇后
In high school,I was prom queen...
和返校节皇后,但是你
...and the homecoming queen and you...
你也在的啊
...were also there.
但是这不是高中,我们现在都是成年人!
But this isn't high school. We're all adults here!
我能要这个吗?
Heckles! Can I have this?
大多数是
For the most part.
如果你把猴子带走 我将失去我生命中重要的人
If you take this monkey,I'll lose an important person in my life.
你可以恨我,请别折磨他
You can hate me if you want,but please do not punish him.
此时你有机会成为大人物
You have a chance to be the bigger person here.
把握机会吧
Take it!
不
No.
那么,我只好告诉你的长官
All right. Then I'll call your supervisor and tell her...
你在我朋友的屁股上开了一枪
...you shot my friend with a dart!
终于能脱去这件衣服,好吗?
It'll be nice to get this off,won't it?
或是这样也不错
Or we can leave it on. That's fine.
配上女鞋就是完整的一套了
With the right pumps,that would be a great little outfit.
抱歉,我对你这么凶
Listen,I'm sorry I was so hard on you before
不,这都是我的错,我差点…
No,it was my fault. I almost lost your
不,他也是你找回来的,你做得很好
Yeah,but you got him back. You were great.
那瓶酒还在
We still have that bottle of wine.
有心情喝杯葡萄酒吗?
Are you in the mood for something grape?
-好呀 -很好
-Sure,that would be good. -All right.
隔壁一定在用吸尘器
The neighbors must be vacuuming.
只要我们在这儿…
Well,as long as we're here...
…不谈那个话题…
...and not on the subject....
我在想…
I was thinking about...
…我们刚刚实在是恶言相向
... how mad we got at each other before.
大概是因为我们…
And maybe it was partially because of how we
-瑞秋? -贝瑞?
-Rachel? -Barry?
我办不到.我无法和明蒂结婚
I can't do it. I can't marry Mindy.
我想我爱的人依然是你
I think I'm still in love with you.
我们得开始锁门了!
We have got to start locking that door!
给我们看看!来嘛!
Show us! Come on!
-很久很久以前 -好吧
-lt was such a long time ago. -Okay,fine. All right.
这是我在“音乐之声”里面,看到范崔普的孩子了吗?
This is me in The Sound of Music. See the von Trapp kids?
因为我挡在他们前面
That's because I'm in front of them.
大修女!
Big nun!
我以为那是阿尔卑斯山
I thought that was an alp.
我的高中时代并不如意
High school wasn't my favorite time.
我爱高中
I loved high school.
四年的舞会,约会和做爱
It was four years of parties,dating and sex and
我和400个男孩上的住宿学校
Well,I went to boarding school with 400 boys.
每次做爱都是一次生活方式的重大抉择
Any sex I had would've involved a major lifestyle choice.
天啊,那不是回到一百万年前?
Doesn't it seem like a million years ago?
我的屁股醒了
My butt cheek is waking up!